Guide to the Sisterhood is Global Institute Records, 1963-2010 and undated, bulk 1980-2002 RL.01185
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Geographical Files Series, 1963-2001 and undated, 13 boxes
  - France
    - 1980-1990, 2001 and undated (Box GEO5)
  - Gambia
    - 1999 (Box GEO5)
  - Germany
    - 1985-1990, 1980s (Box GEO5)
  - Ghana
    - 1999 (Box GEO5)
  - Greece
    - 1984-1992 and undated (Box GEO5)
  - Guatemala
    - 1983-1991 (Box GEO5)
  - Guinea-Bissau, West Africa
    - Fighting two colonialisms: women in Guinea-Bissau, 1979 (Box GEO5)
  - Haiti
    - Tough kid takes the reins in Haiti, 1990 Mar. 15 (Box GEO5)
  - Hungary
    - Undated (Box GEO5)
  - Iceland (Box GEO6)
    - 1985-1988 and undated (Box GEO6)
  - India
    - 1982-2001 and undated, 2 folders (Box GEO6)
    - 1989-2001 (Box GEO6)
  - Indonesia
    - 2000-2001 (Box GEO6)
  - Iran
    - 1967, 1979-1993 and undated (Box GEO6)
  - Iran
    - 1990-2001 and undated, 4 folders (Box GEO6)
  - Iraq
    - 1982-1990, 2000 (Box GEO6)
    - General Federation of Iraqi Women
      - Law and research, 1981 (Box GEO6)
      - Reports and papers, 1979-1981 (Box GEO6)
  - Ireland
    - 1985-1991 and undated (Box GEO6)
  - Israel (Box GEO7)
    - 1977-2001 and undated, 4 folders (Box GEO7)
    - Physicians for human rights, 2001 (Box GEO7)
  - Italy
    - 1979-1985 and undated (Box GEO7)
  - Japan
    - 1977, 1982-1992 and undated (Box GEO7)
    - 1985-1991 (Box GEO7)
  - Jordan
    - 1989-2001 and undated (Box GEO7)
  - Kenya
    - 1985-1999 (Box GEO7)
  - Korea
    - 1989 and undated (Box GEO7)
  - Kuwait
    - Letter from the Khan Law firm, 1991 Nov. 20 (Box GEO7)
  - Latin America
    - General and conferences, 1992-1998 (Box GEO7)
  - Lebanon (Box GEO8)
    - 1994-2001 and undated (Box GEO8)
  - Liberia
    - 1985-1990 (Box GEO8)
  - Malaysia
    - 1963-1998, 5 folders (Box GEO8)
    - Sector of participation and women's economic status, p. 6-239, undated (Box GEO8)
    - Spirits of resistance and capitalist discipline, tropical confluences: rural society, capital, and the state, p.42-241, undated (Box GEO8)
  - Mexico
    - 1987-1990 and undated (Box GEO8)
  - Middle East
    - 1993-2000 (Box GEO8)
  - Morocco
    - 1999-2000 and undated (Box GEO8)
  - Namibia
    - 1985-1990, 1999 (Box GEO8)
  - Nepal
    - 1979-1997 (Box GEO8)
  - Netherlands
    - 1982 and undated (Box GEO8)
  - New Caledonia
    - One law for women, 1990 Feb. 25 (Box GEO8)
  - New Zealand (Box GEO9)
    - 1983-1993 and undated, 3 folders (Box GEO9)
    - Maori women, 1989-1990 and undated (Box GEO9)
  - Nicaragua
    - 1990 and undated (Box GEO9)
  - Nigeria
    - 1990-2001 (Box GEO9)
  - Norway
    - 1982-1990 (Box GEO9)
  - Oman
    - Letter from Afshin Molavi, 1997 Nov. 19 (Box GEO9)
  - Pacific Islands
    - 1988-1992 (Box GEO9)
  - Pakistan
    - 1997-2001 (Box GEO9)
    - Benazir Bhutto, 1990, General, 1982-1992 (Box GEO9)
    - Double jeopardy: police abuse of women in Pakistan, 1992 (Box GEO9)
  - Palestine (Box GEO10)
    - 1983-2001 and undated, 3 folders (Box GEO10)
    - United Nations, 1980-1982 (Box GEO10)
  - Persian Gulf states
    - Women and state in the Arab countries of the Persian Gulf region, 1997 (Box GEO10)
  - Peru
    - 1988-1998 (Box GEO10)
  - Philippines
    - 1980-1990 and undated, 3 folders (Box GEO10)
  - Philippines (Box GEO11)
    - 1985-1999 and undated, 5 folders (Box GEO11)
  - Poland
    - 1981-1992 (Box GEO11)
  - Russia
    - 1984-1990 and undated (Box GEO11)
  - Saudi Arabia
    - 1990-2000 (Box GEO11)
  - Senegal (Box GEO12)
    - Ban on female genital mutilation, 1999 (Box GEO12)
  - Sierra Leone
    - Child victims of war, 1999 (Box GEO12)
  - Serbia
    - 2000-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - Singapore
    - 1987-1989 and undated (Box GEO12)
  - South Africa
    - 1979-1999 (Box GEO12)
  - Southern African region
    - 1992-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - South America
    - Human rights e-mail alerts, 1998-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - South Pacific
    - 1988-1989 and undated (Box GEO12)
  - Spain
    - 1983-1990 and undated (Box GEO12)
  - Sri Lanka
    - 1982-1986 and undated (Box GEO12)
  - Sudan
    - 1983-1999 (Box GEO12)
  - Sweden
    - 1985-1990 (Box GEO12)
  - Switzerland
    - Votes for women rejected - again, 1990 Apr. 30 (Box GEO12)
  - Syria
    - 1999-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - Thailand
    - 1980-1999 and undated (Box GEO12)
  - Tibet
    - Violence against women, 1999 (Box GEO12)
  - Trinidad and Tobago
    - Roles of NGOs and government, 1998 Oct. 26 (Box GEO12)
  - Tunisia
    - 1989-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - Turkey
    - 1990-2001 (Box GEO12)
  - Turkey (Box GEO13)
    - 1996-2001 (Box GEO13)
  - Uganda
    - "Self twice-removed: Ugandan women," by Grace Akello, 1990 (Box GEO13)
  - United States
    - 1983-2000 and undated, 3 folders (Box GEO13)
    - E-mails, 2000-2001 (Box GEO13)
  - Uzbekistan
    - 1999-2001 (Box GEO13)
  - Vanatu
    - "A situation analysis of children and women in Vanatu," 1991 June (Box GEO13)
  - Vietnam
    - 1983-1989 and undated (Box GEO13)
  - Yugoslavia
    - 1985-1999 (Box GEO13)
  - Zimbabwe
    - 1989-2001 (Box GEO13)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1987-2005 and undated, 7 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [Originals closed to use. Some use copies available in the collection. Otherwise, Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
  - Videocassettes Subseries, 1987-2005 and undated
    Recordings include various programs on women's rights and related human rights issues. Some programs were produced by Sisterhood is Global Institute, others by similar organizations in other countries. Several recordings document SIGI-sponsored conferences. Arranged in chronological order. Total running time (TRT), if known, shown in parentheses.
    - Originals OR1-21 (CLOSED)
      - OR1 1987-1988, From Priestess to President, produced by the Women's Media Circle, the Philippines. Format: PAL. (TRT unknown). (Box AV1)
      - OR2 1995, International Women's Peace Fountain. Format: VHS. (TRT 21:30) (Box AV1)
      - OR3 1995, A reporting video on NGO forum on women, Beijing. Format: PAL. (TRT 45:00) (Box AV1)
      - OR4 1996, Feminist Family Values Forum 1: Introduction, Mililani Trask, Austin, Tex. Format: VHS. (TRT 60:00) (Box AV1)
      - OR5 1996, Feminist Family Values Forum 2: Mililani Trask/María Jiménez, Austin. Format: VHS. (TRT: 60:00) (Box AV1)
      - OR6 1996, Feminist Family Values Forum 3: Gloria Steinem, Austin. Format: VHS. (TRT 50:49) (Box AV1)
      - OR7 1996, Feminist Family Values Forum 4: Angela Davis, Austin. Format: VHS. (TRT 52:00) (Box AV1)
      - OR8 1996, Prose, Politics, and Power: Conversations with Muslim Women Leaders. Format: VHS. (TRT 44:20) (Box AV1)
      - OR9 1996, Rights and Wrongs. Format: VHS. (TRT 26:17) (Box AV1)
      - OR10 1997, Sisterhood is Global Institute: Mahnaz Afkhami on CNN's Question and Answer, and CBC's International Hour. Format: VHS. (TRT 33:13) (Box AV1)
      - OR11-12 of 15. 1997, Proceedings from the Rights of Passage Conference, Washington D.C., Parts 1-5. Format: NTSCL., 5 videocassettes (Box AV1)
      - OR13-15 of 15. 1997, Proceedings from the Rights of Passage Conference, Washington D.C., Parts 1-5. Format: NTSCL., 5 videocassettes (Box AV2)
      - OR16 1998, Gems of Hope in Bolivia. Format: VHS. (TRT 10:03) (Box AV2)
      - OR17 1999, Gems of Hope in Bangladesh. Format: VHS. (TRT: 10:23) (Box AV2)
      - OR18 1999, Training Careers in the Digital Age, by Elliott Masie. Format: VHS. (TRT 34:00) (Box AV2)
      - OR19 1999, A Visit to Kabul's Orphanage, Kabul, Afghanistan. Format: VHS. (TRT 25:42) (Box AV2)
      - OR20 Undated, Education seminars of Women's Resource Center in Uzbekistan. Format: PAL. (TRT 10:00) (Box AV2)
      - OR21, Undated, unidentified content. Format: PAL. (TRT 10:00) (Box AV2)
    - Master Copies (Not for reference use)
      - MC2, MC4-7 (Box AV3)
      - MC8-10, MC16-19 (Box AV4)
    - Use Copies
      - UC2, UC 4-10, UC16-19 (Box AV5)
  - Audiocassettes Subseries, 1999, 2005 and undated
    [Originals closed to use. However, use copies available in the collection.]
    - Audiocassette originals OR1-8 (CLOSED) (Box AV6)
      - OR1 1999 Feb. 13, Introduction and session I on keeping money (Box AV6)
      - OR2 1999 Feb. 13, End of discussion on keeping money (Box AV6)
      - 0R3 1999 Feb. 14, Sexual harassment, women harassed in open space (Box AV6)
      - OR4 1999 Feb. 14, Second session on sexual harassment, in public space (Box AV6)
      - OR5 1999 Feb. 20, Discussion on domestic violence, part I (Box AV6)
      - OR6 1999 Feb. 20, Discussion on domestic violence, part II (Box AV6)
      - OR7 1999 Apr. 16, SIGI voice over on domestic violence (Tetu) (Box AV6)
      - OR8 Undated, Radio program on domestic violence in Muslim societies, by Sarina Khan (Box AV6)
    - Master copies MC1-8 (Not for reference use; for creation of use copies.) (Box AV6)
    - Use copies UC1-8 (Box AV7)
- Memorabilia Series, 1996-1997 and undated, 3 boxes
  Includes two large vinyl banners and four smaller cloth banners with SIGI logo.
  - Beijing and Beyond conference banner, 1996 May (Box MEM1)
  - Rights of Passage conference banner, 1997 Sept. (Box MEM2)
  - Sisterhood is Global banners, undated, 4 items (Box MEM3)
- Electronic Formats Series, 1996-2001 and undated
  Contains some financial audit records, files from SIGI’s website, and a large number of intermediary drafts and translations of SIGI’s main publications. Arranged in the original order as the items appeared in the collection. Due to compatibility and software issues, approximately half of the files are not accessible. Please consult with reference staff before coming to use these materials.
  - Administrative Files Series, 1996-2001 and undated
    - Financial Papers Subseries
      - 1996
        - Budget and notes
          - After financial agreement, Disks 001-003 (Box MEM3)
      - 1999
        - Finances, Riggs Repo account
          - Repo account forms, Disks 004-005 (Box MEM3)
    - Funding Files Subseries
      - Combined Federal Campaign for Greater Los Angeles (CFC)
        - Applications
          - For 1998 campaign, Disk 006, 1998 (Box MEM3)
      - National Endowment for Democracy (NED)
        - Building Local Leaders Initiative proposal, Disk 007, 1999-2001 (Box MEM3)
    - Other Records Subseries
      - Contacts
        - Database info, Disks 008-010, undated (Box MEM3)
        - Web
          - Disks 011-012, 1999 (Box MEM3)
          - Disk 013, 1997-1998 (Box MEM3)
  - Publications Series, 1997-2001
    - Claiming Our Rights
      - Arabic
        - Disk 014, 1999 (Box MEM3)
        - Translation of second edition
          - Disks 015-016, 1999 Jan. 19 (Box MEM3)
      - Azeri
        - Disks 017-018, 1999 (Box MEM3)
        - Nassirova, Firanqiz, Disks 019-021 1996, 1998 (Box MEM3)
      - Bangla
        - Preliminary adaptation, Disk 022, 1999 (Box MEM3)
      - English
        - CD 023, 1998 (Box MEM3)
      - French
        - First draft, Amzallag, Yolande, Disk 024, 1996 (Box MEM3)
        - Vivier, Claudine
          - Final edits, Disks 025-029, 1999 Dec. 3 (Box MEM3)
      - Hindi, Disks 030-031, 1999 (Box MEM3)
      - Persian
        - Dr. Hekmat, Hormoz, Disks 033, 1999 (Box MEM3)
      - Russian
        - Disks 034-035, 1999 (Box MEM3)
        - Complete edition with "Premises," Filipova, Olga, Disk 036, 1999 Apr. 26 (Box MEM3)
        - Final version for publication, Filipova, Olga, Disk 037, 1999 Apr. 27 (Box MEM3)
      - Urdu
        - Letter from Vivek Pinto, Disk 038, 1997 Jan. 4 (Box MEM3)
        - Preliminary adaptation
          - Draft, Disk 039, 1999 (Box MEM3)
          - Disk 040, 1999 (Box MEM3)
      - Uzbek
        - Disk 041, 1997, 1999 (Box MEM3)
        - Tokhtakhodjaeva, Marfua, Disks 042-043, 1998-1999 (Box MEM3)
    - In Our Own Words
      - Arabic
        - Khader, Asma, Disk 044, 1999 Nov. 30 (Box MEM3)
      - Facilitator guide, Nancy Flowers
        - Proofs, CD 045, 1999 Dec. 17 (Box MEM3)
      - Russian
        - Disks 046-047, 2000 (Box MEM3)
    - Safe and Secure
      - Arabic
        - Unofficial translation, Elias, Emira, Disk 048, 2001 Mar. (Box MEM3)
      - English
        - Zip disks 049-050, 1998 (Box MEM3)
      - Persian, Disks 051-052, 1999, 2001 (Box MEM3)
      - Russian
        - Disk 053, 1999, 2001 (Box MEM3)
        - Final editing and revision, Filipova, Olga, Disk 054, 2000 June 4 (Box MEM3)
      - Uzbek
        - Disk 055, 1999 (Box MEM3)
    - Strategizing for Safety
      - Call for papers, correspondence, consultant contract, CD 056, 1998 (Box MEM3)
- Oversize Materials
  Contains print materials, chiefly posters from conferences and campaigns, newsletters, and a few large sheets with statistics on women. Arranged according to the series in the main collection and to original location of oversize items.
  - Administrative Files Series, 1988, 1992-1998
    - Membership Files Subseries, 1988, 1997
      - Current members
        - Rivero, Isel: newsletter, 1988 Nov. (Oversize-box OS1)
        - Sonal, Shukla: Sixth National Conference of Women's Movements, declaration and schedule, 1997 Dec. 28-30 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - General
        - Clippings on members
          - Articles, 1988 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Greta Hofmann Nemiroff Subseries, 1998
      - SIGI participation and events
        - Marche Mundial: newsletters, 1998 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Funding Files Subseries, 1992, 1997
      - Foundation for a Compassionate Society
        - General: article, 1992 July 26 (Oversize-box OS1)
        - Vaughan, Genevieve: article, 1997 May 25 (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Project Files Series, 1996-1998 and undated
    - HRE Subseries, 1996-1997
      - Algeria
        - Expanding HRE
          - Meridian International: newsletters, in French, 1997 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Jordan
        - People's Rights: Newspaper of legal research and resource center, 1996-1997 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Other Projects Subseries, 1998 and undated
      - Country Projects
        - Bangladesh
          - Gems of Hope: poster, 1998 (Oversize-box OS1)
        - Jordan
          - Brochures, posters, and photos
            - Poster, undated (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Potential Partnerships
        - Dalit Nepal: posters, undated (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Conferences and Programs Series, 1985-1998, 2000
    - SIGI Subseries, 1998
      - 1998 Sept., Eliminating Violence against Women in Muslim Societies, Amman, Jordan
        - Conference poster
          - Standard (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Other Events Subseries, 1985, 1988, 2000
      - 1985
        - July, The State of the World's Women, Nairobi, Kenya
          - General: newsletters and posters (Oversize-box OS1)
      - 1988
        - Oct., SIGN Dialogues in the Philippines
          - Materials: newsletters (Oversize-box OS1)
      - 2000
        - Mar.-Oct., World March of Women 2000
          - Materials
            - General: poster (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Subject Files Series, 1980, 1991, 1997-1998 and undated
    - Human rights, women's rights
      - Articles and report: newsletters, 1997-1998 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Housing
      - World's women data sheets, 1980 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Violence against women
      - Domestic
        - Articles, newsletters, reports
          - Poster, undated, 1 item (Oversize-box OS1)
      - General
        - Articles and papers
          - Poster, undated, 1 item (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Prostitution and trafficking
        - Articles, newsletters, reports: poster, undated
          - Poster, undated, 1 item (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Women and the environment: newsletter, 1991 (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Organizations Series, 1984-2000 and undated
    - Amnesty International: newsletter, 1996 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Association for Women in Development: newsletter, article, 1996, 1999 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Institute of Women's Studies, Lahore: poster, 1999-2000 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Mambobeh Sadria Enterprise: newsletters, undated (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Population Crisis Committee: statistics and index sheets, 1987-1988, 1992 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Population Reference Bureau: statistics on world's women, 1995 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - Shirkat-Gah: newsletter, 1990 (Oversize-box OS2)
    - UNICEF: report, 1994 (Oversize-box OS2)
  - Geographic Files Series, 1983-2001 and undated
    - Articles, clippings, and newsletters, 1983-1999 and undated (Oversize-box OS2)
      From materials related to Africa, Denmark, Egypt, France, Greece, Israel, Japan, and Jordan.
    - Articles, clippings, and posters, 1987-2001 and undated (Oversize-box OS2)
      From materials related to Kenya, Latin America, Malaysia, New Zealand, Nigeria, Oman, the Philippines, Sweden, Turkey, and the United States.
- Accession (2009-0070), 1985-2003, 14 boxes
  The addition (2009-0070) (5850 items; 7.8 lin. ft.; dated 1985-2003) contains administrative records and correspondence, financial reports and documents, legal documents, membership information, annual reports, and publicity files. Also included are 20 cassette tapes recording the Sisterhood is Global Strategy Meeting (1984), founding the Institute, and 11 floppy discs that have been transferred to Duke's Electronic Records server. This addition has not been processed. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
  - General financial records (audits, investment information, bank and tax documents), 2000-2002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Administrative documents, 2002 (Box 1)
  - General financial records (audits, tax documents) (Box 2)
  - Membership information and correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Bylaws, 1980s (Box 3)
  - 501(c)(3) status files, mid-1980s (Box 3)
  - Membership information and correspondence (Box 3)
  - Legal documents, 1986-1990s (Box 3)
  - First Women's Bank information (Box 3)
  - SIGNET financial documents (Box 4)
  - Constitution, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Annual reports, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Member addresses (Box 4)
  - Robin Morgan to New Zealand office correspondence (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
  - Grant files, 1990s-2002 (Box 5)
  - General correspondence, Canada, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Karen Berry correspondence with New Zealand, 1980s-1990s (Box 5)
  - General SIGI information and correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 6)
  - SIGI in Montreal administrative and financial files (Box 6)
  - General SIGI information and correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 7)
  - SIGI Bethesda, MD, office data (Box 7)
  - SIGI relocation to Canada, 2000 (Box 7)
  - SIGI Bethesda, MD, office data (Box 8)
  - Afkhami resignation and controversy (Box 8)
  - Robin Morgan speech to UN, International Women's Day (Box 8)
  - Executive branch, 1999 (Box 8)
  - SIGI operational files: tax, legal, insurance documents, audits, 1999-2003 (Box 8)
  - SIGI operational files: tax, legal, audits, website files, correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box 9)
  - Accounts (Box 9)
  - SIGI Steering Committee (SC) meetings, 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - SIGI Steering Committee (SC) meetings, 1999-2003 (Box 11)
  - NGO status (Box 11)
  - Director reports, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Constitution and bylaws, 2000 (Box 11)
  - NGO files, tax files (Box 12)
  - Brochure and logo files, 1980s-2000 (Box 12)
  - Publicity and other administrative files, Montreal (Box 12)
  - SIGNewsletter (Box 12)
  - SIGI Annual Reports, 1993-2000 (Box 12)
  - SIGI Annual Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 13)
  - Transition binder, 2000 (Box 13)
  - UN and NGO files (Box 13)
  - Complete audiotapes (20) of Sisterhood is Global Strategy Meeting, 1984 (Box 14)
- Accession (2015-0148), 1982-2010
  - Administrative files and correspondence, 1982-2010 (Box 1, Box 2)